So far we have created a play field
これまでに、プレイフィールドと
and a Player game object
Player ゲームオブジェクトを作成し
and we have the player moving
プレイヤーの動きを
under our control.
うまく制御できるようになりました
In this lesson we'll create
ここでは、
the collectable objects
プレイヤーが取得する
for our player to pick up.
アイテムを作成します
First open the Sprites folder.
最初に Sprites フォルダーを開きます
Drag the sprite Pickup
スプライトの Pickup をドラッグして
in to the hierarchy.
Hierarchy ウィンドウに置きます
You'll notice after dragging in
ドラッグしても
the Pickup sprite that we
Pickup スプライトがまだ見えないことに
still can't see it.
気づくでしょう
That's because it's being rendered
これは、Pickup スプライトが
behind both the Player
Player と Background スプライトの背後に
and Background sprites.
レンダリングされたからです
To bring it forward we
前面に持ってくるには
need to set the sorting layer
Sprite Renderer コンポーネントの
in the sprite renderer component.
Sorting Layer を設定する必要があります
Set the sorting layer to Pickups.
Sorting Layer をPickups にします
Now the Player game object
さて、まだPlyer ゲームオブジェクトが
is still in the way.
邪魔です
This is because the Player
なぜなら、 Player ソ―ティングレイヤーは
sorting layer is in front
Pickup ソ―ティングレイヤーの
of the Pickups sorting layer.
前面にあるからです
Let's temporarily deactivate
一時的に Player ゲームオブジェクトを
the Player game object.
非アクティブにしましょう
Select the Player game object
Player ゲームオブジェクトを選び
and deselect the checkbox
名前のフィールドのチェックマークを
in front of the Name field.
はずします
This is the game object's Active checkbox.
これは、ゲームオブジェクトを非アクティブにするチェックボックスです
Deselecting it will deactivate
これを非選択にすると
the game object in the scene.
シーンでゲームオブジェクトを非アクティブにします
This will give us a clear working space
これで、ご覧のように
for our new pickup object
新しい Pickup オブジェクトを見られる
which we can now see.
見通しの良い作業スペースができました
Focus the scene view camera on the
Pickup オブジェクトをハイライトして
pickup object by highlighting it
カーソルを Scene ビューに置きF キーを押して
and pressing the F key whilst
そのオブジェクト上の Scene ビューの
the cursor is over the scene view.
カメラにフォーカスします
So that we can collide with the pickup
これで、Pickup と衝突できるようになります
let's add a circle collider 2D
Circle collider 2D コンポーネントを
component to it.
加えましょう
With the pickup highlighted click
Pickup をハイライトしておいて
Add Component - Physics 2D
Add Component > Physics 2D
then Circle Collider 2D.
Circle Collider 2D の順に選びます
Adjust the Radius property
Circle collider 2D の
of the circle collider 2D
Radius プロパティーをドラッグして調整し
so that it fits the sprite artwork visually b
Collider 2D がスプライトに
by dragging in the Radius field.
見た目で合うようにします。
To be effective the collectable
効果を上げるために、アイテムは
must attract the attention of the player.
プレイヤーの目を引くべきです
So let's make the object more attractive.
ですから、もっと目立つ見た目にしましょう
There's one thing I feel certainly
確実にプレイヤーの注意を引くと思うものが
attracts the attention of a player
1 つあります
and that is movement.
それは動きです
So let's rotate our pickup.
Pickup を回転させてみましょう
One way to do this is with a script.
方法の1 つはスクリプトを使用する方法です
With the pickup object still selected
Pickup オブジェクトを選択したままで
use the Add Component button
Inspector のAdd Component ボタンを
in the inspector.
押します
Let's create a new script called Rotator.
Rotator という新しいスクリプトを作成しましょう
Click Create and Add to confirm
Create and Add をクリックして作成し
and let's organise the script by
それを Scripts フォルダーに
placing it in the Scripts folder.
入れます
Open the Scripts folder and
Scripts フォルダーを開き
double click to open it for editing.
そのスクリプトをダブルクリックして開きます
We want the sprite to spin and we want
私たちは、スプライトをこのスクリプトを使って
to do it with this script.
スピンさせようとしています
Let's remove the sample code
まず、使わないサンプルコードを
we don't need.
削除します
We will not be using forces
力は使わないので
so we can use Update
Fixed Update よりむしろ
rather than Fixed Update.
Update を使用します
We want to rotate the object every frame.
すべてのフレームでオブジェクトを回転させます
To make the pickups spin we
Pickups を回転させるには
don't want to set the transform rotation
transform rotation は設定したくありませんが
but we want to rotate the transform.
transform を回転させる必要があります
Type Transform inside Update.
Update の中に transform を入力します
Select it and hold down the
それを選択し、
control key on windows or the command
Windows の場合は Ctrl キーと ' を
key on mac and type '
Mac の場合は Command キーと ' を押します
Again this brings up the page
これにより transform で検索されたページが
with a search term Transform.
表示されます
Select Transform.
Transform を選択します
Scroll down until you see Transform's public functions.
Transform のパブリック関数を見つけるまで、スクロールダウンします
There are two main ways to affect the transform.
Transform に影響を与えるには 2 通りあります
These are Translate and Rotate.
Translate と Rotate です
Translate moves the game object
Translate は transform を使って
using it's transform.
ゲームオブジェクトを動かします
Rotate rotates the game object
Rotate はtransform を使って
We will use rotate.
ここでは Rotate を使います
So let's click on the link.
リンクをクリックしましょう
This brings up the page for Transform.Rotate.
Transform.Rotate のページが開きます
Note again the two signatures.
シグネチャが2つあることに注意してください
One is using a vector3
1 つは vector3 を使用し
and the other is using 3
他方は 3 つの float 値
float values for X, Y or Z.
X, Y, Z を使用します
Both have the optional parameter
両方ともに
Space which we will
オプションのパラメーター Space がありますが
leave at default for this lesson.
このレッスンではデフォルトのままにしておきます
Again we will choose the most simple
ここでも、方向に vector3 のみを使う
form that only uses the vector3 for direction.
最も簡易なフォームを選びます
Let's return to our code.
コードに戻りましょう
After transform,
transform の後に
making sure that transform is written to
transform は小文字の t で
begin with a lowercase t,
始めるように注意してください。その後に
write .rotate (new Vector3 (0, 0, 45))
.rotate (new Vector3 (0, 0, 45)) と入力します
This means we'll rotate
つまり
around the Z axis.
Z 軸の周りを回転するということです
Now this action also needs
この動きはスムーズで
to be smooth and frame rate independent
フレーム率に関係ないことが必要です
so we need to multiply the vector3 value
それでvector3 値を
by Time.deltaTime.
Time.deltaTime で乗じます
It is worth noting that even
覚えておくとよいのは
though we are working with a 2D
私たちは 2D スプライトを使っていますが
sprite we are using a vector3
アイテムの Transform を回転させるために
to rotate the collectable's transform.
vector3 を使用するということです
This is because the transform
この理由は
of the 2D sprite
2D スプライトの transform も
still exists in the 3D volume.
3D ボリューム内に存在できるからです
When using the transform component
Transform コンポーネントを
with 2D objects we simply
2D オブジェクトと使うときは
ignore the axis we don't need.
不要な軸を無視します
Now that we are done with our Rotator script
さあ、Rotator スクリプトを終了しました
save this script and return to Unity.
これを保存して Unity に戻ります
Let's test by entering play mode.
プレイモードにしてテストしてみましょう
And we can see our pickup object rotates.
Pickup オブジェクトが回転しているのを確認しました
Let's exit play mode.
プレイモードを閉じましょう
Okay, we have the start of a working
Pickup オブジェクトの作業の
pickup object.
第一歩は終わりました
Next we want to place these pickups
次に、この Pickup を
around the game area.
ゲームエリアの周囲に置きます
But before we do this we need to do
ただし、その前に
one important step.
1 つ重要な手順があります
We need to make our pickup object
このPickup オブジェクトを
in to a prefab.
プレハブにすることです
Remember, a prefab is an
プレハブはアセットで、そこには
asset that contains a template
ゲームオブジェクト、またはゲームオブジェクトファミリーの
or blueprint of a game object
テンプレートかブループリントが
or game object family.
含まれています
We create a prefab from an
存在するゲームオブジェクトや
existing game object or game object family
ゲームオブジェクトファミリーからプレハブを作れます
and once we create it
1 度プレハブを作成すると
we can use it in any scene
現在のプロジェクトのどんなシーンででも
in our current project.
使用することができます
With a prefab of our pickup object
Pickup オブジェクトのプレハブで
we will be able to make changes to
シーン内の単独のインスタンス
a single instance in our scene
または、プレハブアセットそのものを
or to the prefab asset itself.
変更することができます
And all of the pickup objects in our
そしてその変更によって
game will be updated with those changes.
ゲームの Pickup オブジェクトすべてが更新されます
You'll notice we already have a folder
ご覧のように、プレハブを保存するフォルダーが
to hold our prefabs.
すでに用意されています
Let's drag the Pickup game object
Pickup ゲームオブジェクトをドラッグして
from our hierarchy and place
Hierarchy から
it in to our Prefabs folder.
Prefabs フォルダーに移します
When we drag and item from our hierarchy
アイテムを Hierarchy から
in to our project view
Project ビューにドラッグするとき
we create a new prefab
Project に新しいプレハブアセットが
asset in our project.
作成されます
Before we spread our collectables
アイテムをゲームエリアに
around the game area we should create
ばらまく前に
a new game object
複数の Pickup を記憶し
to hold our pickups and
Hierarchy を整理するために
to help organise our hierarchy.
1 つの新しいゲームオブジェクトを作成します
Let's create a new game object.
新しいゲームオブジェクトを作成しましょう
And call it Pickups.
そして、Pickups と名付けます
Check the transform to make sure our
Transform を見て
Pickups holder object
Pickupsオブジェクトが
is at origin, or (0, 0, 0).
起点、つまり  (0, 0, 0) にあることを確認します
And if not use the component
そうでない場合は、コンポーネントのコンテキストメニューを使い
context menu to reset it.
リセットします
Next drag our Pickup game object on to it.
次に、Pickup ゲームオブジェクトを Pickups の上にドラッグします
Now we want to spread a
さて、これらの Pickup オブジェクトを
number of these pickup objects
プレイエリアに
around the play area.
たくさんばらまきます
Make sure the pickup game object is
親でなく Pickup ゲームオブジェクトが
selected, and not the parent.
選択されているのを確認します
Now let's back out a little
すこしズームアウトして
so we can see the entire game area.
ゲームエリア全体が見えるようにします
Click and drag the pickup game object
Pickup ゲームオブジェクトをクリック & ドラッグし
to move it in to the
最初に拾う位置に
first pickup position.
動かします
I'm going to place mine at the top of the playing area.
私はプレイエリアの一番上に置くことにします
With the game object still selected
ゲームオブジェクトを選択したままで
duplicate it.
複製します
This can be done either by selecting
複製は、Edit > Duplicate の順で選ぶか
Edit - Duplicate, or by using the hot key combination.
ホットキーのコンビネーションで作成できます
This is command-D on mac,
Mac ではcommand-D
or control-D on windows.
Windows では control-D です
Now let's position the
さて、プレハブの 2 番目のインスタンスを
second instance of the prefab.
配置しましょう
Using the hot keys we will
ホットキーを使って
create a few more, placing them
もうちょっと作成し
around the play area.
プレイエリアに置きます
Okay, I've created 12.
私は、ここに 12 個作りました
Let's hit play and test.
再生を押して、テストしましょう
Excellent, these pickup prefabs
よろしい、これらの Pickup プレハブは
are working great.
うまく作動しています
In the next assignment we'll learn how to
次のレッスンでは
pick them up and to count them.
アイテムを拾う方法と数え方を学びます